Guide to the Mary Fosselman Papers, 1931-1941 UA 318
Woodson Research Center, Rice University, Houston, Texas
Mary Fosselman Papers
1931-1941
Woodson Research Center, Rice University, Houston, Texas https://library.rice.edu/woodson
Fosselman, Mary
UA 318
2.5 Linear Feet (3 boxes)
This collection consists of the personal and academic papers of Mary Fosselman.
Biographical / Historical
Mary Fosselman was born in Illinois on September 15, 1916. After living briefly in Houston, Missouri, and Arkansas, her family finally settled in Houston in 1930. She then attended Milby High School. Upon graduation, she went to the Rice Institute and graduated with a BA in 1938.
After graduation, Fosselman took classes at Houston Business College and received a diploma in Stenography. She eventually worked at Schlumberger where she retired in 1981. Fosselman passed away in 2006.
Scope and Contents
This collection consists of the personal and academic papers of Mary Fosselman. There are diaries that she kept while she attended Milby High School, the Rice Institute, and Houston Business College. The diaries also document her first two jobs in Houston. Her diaries also include ephemera like football scorecards and theater programs.
Her academic papers include her notes, tests, and assignments in high school, at the Rice Institute, in education courses at the University of Houston, and the Houston Business College. There is also some correspondence, a diploma, and a graduate photograph.
Conditions Governing Access
This material is open for research. Stored off-site at the Library Service Center. Please request this material via woodson@rice.edu or call 713-348-2586.
Accruals
Additional materials are not expected for this collection.
Index Terms
Subjects
Universities and colleges; Social life and customs; Rice University -- History; Women
Document Types
diaries
- Series I: Personal papers, 1932-1941; 162778
  General Note
  The following diaries not only record Fosselman's daily life, but also contain event programs, postcards, and letters.
  - Diary, August 1, 1931-May 4, 1933; 162783 (Box 1, Folder 1)
  - Diary - Volume I, September 5, 1933-September 4, 1934; 162784 (Box 1, Folder 2)
  - Diary - Volume II, September 5, 1934-September 5, 1935; 162785 (Box 1, Folder 3)
  - Diary - Volume III, September 5, 1935-September 3, 1936; 162786 (Box 1, Folder 4)
  - Diary - Volume IV, September 5, 1936-September 5, 1937; 162787 (Box 1, Folder 5)
  - Diary - Volume V - part 1, September 5, 1937-September 5, 1938; 162788 (Box 1, Folder 6)
  - Diary - Volume V - part 2, September 5, 1937-September 5, 1938; 162789 (Box 1, Folder 7)
  - Diary - Volume VI, September 5, 1938-September 5, 1939; 162790 (Box 1, Folder 8)
  - Diary - Volume VII, September 5, 1939-September 5, 1940; 162791 (Box 1, Folder 9)
  - Diary - Volume VIII - part 1 and 2, September 5, 1940-September 5, 1941; 162792 (Box 1, Folder 10)
  - Diary - Volume VIII - part 3, September 5, 1940-September 5, 1941; 162793 (Box 1, Folder 11)
- Series II: Academic papers, 1933-1939; 162779
  - Subseries A: High School, 1933-1934; 162780
    - Civics II, 1933-1934; 162794 (Box 1, Folder 12)
    - Clothing I and II, 1933, 1934; 162795 (Box 1, Folder 13)
    - English VII, 1933-1934; 162796 (Box 1, Folder 14)
    - English VIII, 1933-1934; 162797 (Box 1, Folder 15)
    - Sewing I and II, 1933-1934; 162798 (Box 1, Folder 16)
  - Subseries B: Houston Business College and University of Houston, 1936-1939; 162781
    - Education 310 (1 of 2), 1936-1937; 162799 (Box 1, Folder 17)
    - Education 310 (2 of 2), 1936-1937; 162800 (Box 1, Folder 18)
    - Education 410, November 1937; 162801 (Box 1, Folder 19)
    - Education 435, 1937; 162802 (Box 1, Folder 20)
    - Filing, 1939; 162803 (Box 1, Folder 21)
    - Health Education 232, 1937; 162804 (Box 1, Folder 22)
    - Scientific Dictation, 1939; 162805 (Box 1, Folder 23)
    - Houston Business College Diploma, December 1939; 162806 (Box 2, Folder 1)
  - Subseries C: Rice Institute, 1934-1938; 162782
    - Chemistry 100/200, 1934-1936; 162807 (Box 2, Folder 2)
    - Chemistry 200, 1935-1936; 162808 (Box 2, Folder 3)
    - Correspondence, 1934-1938; 162809 (Box 2, Folder 4)
    - English 100, 1934-1935; 162810 (Box 2, Folder 5)
    - English 310 (1 of 2), 1936-1937; 162811 (Box 2, Folder 6)
    - English 310 (2 of 2), 1936-1937; 162812 (Box 2, Folder 7)
    - French 100, 1935-1936; 162813 (Box 2, Folder 8)
    - French 200, 1937; 162814 (Box 2, Folder 9)
    - Graduation photograph, June 6, 1938; 162815 (Box 2, Folder 10)
    - History 100 (1 of 2), 1934-1935; 162816 (Box 2, Folder 11)
    - History 100 (2 of 2), 1934-1935; 162817 (Box 2, Folder 12)
    - History 250 (1 of 2), 1935-1936; 162818 (Box 2, Folder 13)
    - History 250 (2 of 2), 1935-1936; 162819 (Box 2, Folder 14)
    - "Joseph Priestly in America" - The Lady Geddes Contest submission, May 3, 1935; 162820 (Box 2, Folder 15)
    - Mathematics 100, 1934-1935; 162821 (Box 2, Folder 16)
    - Newsclippings, 1935; 162822 (Box 3, Folder 1)
    - Psychology 300 (1 of 2), 1936-1937; 162823 (Box 3, Folder 2)
    - Psychology 300 (2 of 2), 1936-1937; 162824 (Box 3, Folder 3)
    - Spanish 210, 1934-1935; 162825 (Box 3, Folder 4)
    - Spanish 300, 1935-1936; 162826 (Box 3, Folder 5)
    - Spanish 410, 1936-1937; 162827 (Box 3, Folder 6)